homeandgardenideas.com 2012-11-02

# Privacy Policy | Home & Garden Ideas

Consumer Privacy Statement

THE WRITERS NETWORK at Pronto.com, an IAC Company

Pronto LLC, a wholly owned IAC company, owns and operates The Writers Network which operates [www.writersnetwork.com](https://www.writersnetwork.com/), [www.homeandgardenideas.com](http://www.homeandgardenideas.com/), [www.moneyandbusiness.com](http://www.moneyandbusiness.com/), [www.beautyandstyle.com](http://www.beautyandstyle.com/), [www.sportsandfitnessideas.com](http://www.sportsandfitnessideas.com/) and [www.informationvine.com](http://www.informationvine.com/).  IAC includes over 60 brands including, in addition to Pronto, Ask.com, Match.com, Citysearch, UrbanSpoon, ServiceMagic, Dictionary.com and many others. For a list of all of IAC's businesses, please visit [www.iac.com](http://www.iac.com/). In order to help customers clearly understand our data collection and use practices, IAC has decided to have its businesses follow a standard set of privacy practices and use a standard format to describe their privacy practices. The following Consumer Privacy statement applies to all IAC businesses. In addition, Pronto LLC has implemented this Privacy Policy for [www.writersnetwork.com](https://www.writersnetwork.com/), [www.homeandgardenideas.com](http://www.homeandgardenideas.com/), [www.moneyandbusiness.com](http://www.moneyandbusiness.com/), [www.beautyandstyle.com](http://www.beautyandstyle.com/), [www.sportsandfitnessideas.com](http://www.sportsandfitnessideas.com/) and [www.informationvine.com](http://www.informationvine.com/) consistent with the IAC privacy commitment and standard privacy policy format. Please review both this Consumer Privacy statement and this web site's complete privacy policy. 

At IAC, we respect the privacy of our users and the importance of the information they entrust to us. We summarize below the basic information policies and practices in place on all IAC websites. To read the entire Privacy Policy for The Writers Network and its operated sites, please see below.  

Information we may collect  |  Read More Below

We may collect information that can identify you ("personal information"), such as your name and email address, (i) when you (or other users) provide it to us when using our website or in some other manner, or (ii) from other IAC businesses, from our business partners, and from other third parties. We may combine the personal information that we receive from different sources. 

We also may collect other types of information in the following ways when you visit our website: 

Our server logs automatically collect information, such as your IP address, your browser type and language, and the date and time of your visit, which helps us track users' movements around our site and understand trends. 

  * We may assign your computer one or more cookies to the relevant section of the Privacy Policy which may collect information to facilitate access to our website and to personalize your online experience.
  * We may use standard Internet tools, such as web beacons which collect information that tracks your use of our website and enables us to customize our services and advertisements.
  * We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Should we ever do so, we will comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act.

Information others may collect  |  Read More Below

We may allow third-party advertising companies or ad networks to display advertisements on our websites. 

  * We do not provide any personal information to these companies.
  * These companies may use tracking tools, such as cookies to collect information about computers used to view or interact with their advertisements.
  * Some of these companies may be members of the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/), which offers consumers the ability to opt out of ad targeting by all member companies.

If you post information about yourself or others, or communicate with others using our website, please note that we cannot control who reads your postings or what they do with the information you provide. We encourage you to use caution in posting personal information.

How we may use information we collect  |  Read More Below We may use information to:  

  * Fulfill your requests for products and services;
  * Offer products and services that may be of interest to you;
  * Customize the advertising and content that you see on our website;
  * Facilitate use of our website;
  * Manage your account and your preferences;
  * Analyze use of and improve our website, products and services;
  * Identify and protect against fraudulent transactions and other misuses of our website; and
  * Enforce our Terms of Service.

With whom we may share information we collect  |  Read More Below

We will not share your personal information with others except as indicated below, or except when we inform you in advance and give you the opportunity to opt out. We may share personal information with:

  * Service providers, such as credit-card payment processors, performing services on our behalf;
  * Other IAC businesses; and
  * Other businesses with which we partner or which we carefully select to offer you products, services, and promotions through our website or offline.

We may share aggregated, non-personal information in any of the above situations and also with advertisers and others.

Your choices  |  Read More Below

You may choose:

  * Not to provide personal information, although that may result in your inability to obtain certain services or use certain features of our website;
  * To stop receiving promotional emails or newsletters from us by sending an email to the contact address at the bottom of this policy;
  * To delete or decline cookies by changing your browser settings, although if you do so, some of the features or services of our website may not function properly;
  * To review and update your personal information by contacting us at the email address below or, if you have an online account on our website, by logging into that account.

Security  |  Read More Below

We take appropriate physical, electronic, and other security measures to help safeguard personal information from unauthorized access, alteration, or disclosure.

Changes to The Writers Network Privacy Policy

We may occasionally update The Privacy Policy applicable to [www.writersnetwork.com](http://www.writersnetwork.com/ "www.writersnetwork.com"), [www.homeandgardenideas.com](http://www.homeandgardenideas.com/ "www.homeandgardenideas.com"), [www.moneyandbusiness.com](http://www.moneyandbusiness.com/ "www.moneyandbusiness.com"), [www.beautyandstyle.com](http://www.beautyandstyle.com/ "www.beautyandstyle.com"), [www.sportsandfitnessideas.com](http://www.sportsandfitnessideas.com/ "www.sportsandfitnessideas.com") and [www.informationvine.com](http://www.informationvine.com/ "www.informationvine.com") to reflect changes in our practices and services. If we make material changes in the way we collect, use, or share your personal information, we will notify you by sending you an email to the email address you most recently provided to us and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our website.

How to contact us

If you have any questions about this summary, our Privacy Policy, or our information practices, please contact us by email or postal mail below:

Privacy Officer

The Writers Network

Pronto, LLC.

555 West 18th Street

4th Floor

New York, NY 10011

© 2012 IAC/InterActiveCorp. All rights reserved.

* * *

THE WRITERS NETWORK

PRIVACY POLICY

Your Privacy Rights

Last updated November 5, 2010

Pronto, LLC. (ìProntoî) owns and operates The Writers Network and [www.writersnetwork.com](https://www.writersnetwork.com/), [www.homeandgardenideas.com](http://www.homeandgardenideas.com/), [www.moneyandbusiness.com](http://www.moneyandbusiness.com/), [www.beautyandstyle.com](http://www.beautyandstyle.com/), , [www.sportsandfitnessideas.com](http://www.sportsandfitnessideas.com/) and [www.informationvine.com](http://www.informationvine.com/).  Pronto respects the privacy of our users and has developed this Privacy Policy to demonstrate its commitment to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy is intended to describe for you, as an individual who is a user of  [www.homeandgardenideas.com](http://www.homeandgardenideas.com/ "www.homeandgardenideas.com"), [www.writersnetwork.com](http://www.writersnetwork.com/ "www.writersnetwork.com"), [www.beautyandstyle.com](http://www.beautyandstyle.com/ "www.beautyandstyle.com"), [www.moneyandbusiness.com](http://www.moneyandbusiness.com/ "www.moneyandbusiness.com"), [www.sportsandfitnessideas.com](http://www.sportsandfitnessideas.com/ "www.sportsandfitnessideas.com"), [www.informationvine.com](http://www.informationvine.com/ "www.informationvine.com") or our other websites within The Writers Network, which link to this Privacy Policy and which are covered by this Privacy Policy, the information we collect, how that information may be used, with whom it may be shared, and your choices about such uses and disclosures.

We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy carefully when using The Writers Network and/or [www.homeandgardenideas.com](http://www.homeandgardenideas.com/ "www.homeandgardenideas.com"), [www.writersnetwork.com](http://www.writersnetwork.com/ "www.writersnetwork.com"), [www.beautyandstyle.com](http://www.beautyandstyle.com/ "www.beautyandstyle.com"), [www.moneyandbusiness.com](http://www.moneyandbusiness.com/ "www.moneyandbusiness.com"), [www.sportsandfitnessideas.com](http://www.sportsandfitnessideas.com/ "www.sportsandfitnessideas.com"), [www.informationvine.com](http://www.informationvine.com/ "www.informationvine.com"). By using our website or our services within The Writers Network, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.  Pronto is a part of the IAC/InterActiveCorp family of businesses [[www.iac.com]](http://www.iac.com/), which includes Ask.com, Citysearch, UrbanSpoon, Match.com, ServiceMagic, Dictionary.com, and many others.

If you have any questions about our privacy practices, please refer to the end of this Privacy Policy for information on how to contact us.

Information we collect about you

In General. We may collect personal information that can identify you such as your name and email address and other information that does not identify you. When you provide personal information through our website, the information may be sent to servers located in the United States and other countries around the world.

  * Information you provide. We may collect and store any personal information you enter on our website or provide to us in some other manner. This includes identifying information, such as your name, address and e-mail address. We also may request information about your interests and activities, your gender and age, zip code, and other demographic information.  If you sign up to become a writer in The Writersí Network, we may collect and store additional personal information which will be subject to the terms and conditions of any agreement you enter with Pronto in the sign up process.
  * Information from other sources. We may also periodically obtain both personal and non-personal information about you from other IAC businesses, business partners, contractors and other third parties. Examples of information that we may receive include: updated delivery and address information, purchase history, and additional demographic information.
  * Information about others. We may also collect and store personal information about other people that you provide to us. If you use our website to send others (friends, relatives, colleagues, etc.) information that may interest them or messages (such as invitations to join a network) or other purpose that our service mail allow through our system, we may store your personal information, and the personal information of each such recipient.

Use of cookies and other technologies to collect information. We use various technologies to collect information from your computer and about your activities on our site.  

  * Information collected automatically. We automatically collect information from your browser when you visit our website. This information includes your IP address, your browser type and language, operating system, screen resolution access times, the content of any undeleted cookies that your browser previously accepted from us (see "Cookies"), and the referring website address.
  * Cookies. When you visit our website, we may assign your computer one or more cookies, to facilitate access to our site and to personalize your online experience. Through the use of a cookie, we also may automatically collect information about your online activity on our site, such as the web pages you visit, the links you click, and the searches you conduct on our site. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. If you choose to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in or use some of the interactive features offered on our website.
  * Other Technologies. We may use standard Internet technology, such as web beacons and other similar technologies, to track your use of our site. We also may include web beacons in promotional [or other] e-mail messages or newsletters to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. The information we obtain in this manner enables us to customize the services we offer our website visitors to deliver targeted advertisements and to measure the overall effectiveness of our online advertising, content, programming or other activities.
  * Information collected by third-parties. We may allow third-parties, including our authorized service providers, IAC companies, advertising companies, and ad networks, to display advertisements on our site. These companies may use tracking technologies, such as cookies or web beacons these should be a link to the relevant section of the Privacy Policy, to collect information about users who view or interact with their advertisements. Our website does not provide any personal information to these third parties. This information allows them to deliver targeted advertisements and gauge their effectiveness. Some of these third-party advertising companies may be advertising networks that are members of the Network Advertising Initiative, which offers a single location to opt out of ad targeting from member companies ([www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)).

How we use the information we collect

In general. We may use information that we collect about you to:

  * deliver services that you have requested;
  * manage your account and provide you with customer support;
  * allows other users of our service to learn about you and your interests through information you make available on your profile;
  * perform research and analysis about your use of, or interest in, our service or content, or products, services or content offered by others;
  * communicate with you by e-mail, postal mail, telephone and/or mobile devices about products or services that may be of interest to you either from us, our sister IAC companies or other third parties;
  * develop and display content and advertising tailored to your interests on our site and other sites;
  * verify your eligibility and deliver prizes in connection with contests and sweepstakes;
  * enforce our terms and conditions;
  * manage our business and
  * perform functions as otherwise described to you at the time of collection.

Job applicants. If your personal information is submitted through our website when applying for a position with our company, the information will be used solely in connection with considering and acting upon your application. We may retain your personal information for a period of time, but only for the purpose of considering your application for current or future available positions. This information may be shared with our sister IAC companies for the purpose of evaluating your qualifications for other available positions, as well as with third-party service providers retained by us to collect, maintain and analyze candidate submissions for job postings.

The Writers Network Sign Up. If your personal information is submitted through The Writers Network web site at [www.writersnetwork.com](https://www.writersnetwork.com/) when enrolling to become a writer for that service, the information will be used solely in connection with considering and acting upon your application and, if accepted, in managing your account, making payments to you and remitting information to the proper governmental authorities as required.  If your relationship with The Writers Network terminates for any reason, we may keep a copy of your information for our record keeping purposes. 

Please review "Your choices about collection and use of your information" below.

With whom we share your information:

We want you to understand when and with whom we may share personal or other information we have collected about you or your activities on our web site or while using our services.

  * Personal information. We do not share your personal information with others except as indicated below or when we inform you and give you an opportunity to opt out of having your personal information shared. We may share personal information with:
  * Authorized service providers: We may share your personal information with our authorized service providers that perform certain services on our behalf. These services may include performing business and sales analysis, supporting our website functionality and connectivity, and supporting any contests, sweepstakes, surveys and/or other features that may be offered through our website. These service providers may have access to personal information needed to perform their functions but are not permitted to share or use such information for any other purposes.
  * Business partners: When you engage in promotions offered through our website or our services, we may share personal information with the businesses with which we partner to offer you those products, services, promotions, contests and/or sweepstakes. When you elect to engage in a particular merchant's offer or program, you authorize us to provide your email address and other information to that merchant.
  * Other IAC businesses. We are part of the IAC family of businesses (go to [www.iac.com](http://www.iac.com/ "www.iac.com") for a listing of these businesses). We may share information we collect, including personal information, with the IAC companies. Sharing information with our IAC companies enables us to provide you with information about a variety of products and services that might interest you. All IAC companies comply with the IAC Consumer Privacy Statement. Our IAC companies also will comply with applicable privacy and security laws and, at a minimum, in any commercial e-mail they send to you, will give you the opportunity to choose not to receive such e-mail messages in the future.
  * Other Situations. We also may disclose your information:
    * In response to a subpoena or similar investigative demand, a court order, or a request for cooperation from a law enforcement or other government agency; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases, we may raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us.
    * When we believe disclosure is appropriate in connection with efforts to investigate, prevent, or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing; to protect and defend the rights, property or safety of our company, our users, our employees, or others; to comply with applicable law or cooperate with law enforcement; or to enforce our website terms and conditions or other agreements or policies.
    * In connection with a substantial corporate transaction, such as the sale of our business, a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

Any third parties to whom we may disclose personal information may have their own privacy policies which describe how they use and disclose personal information. Those policies will govern use, handling and disclosure of your personal information once we have shared it with those third parties as described in this Privacy Policy. If you want to learn more about their privacy practices, we encourage you to visit the websites of those third parties. These entities or their servers may be located either inside or outside the United States.

Aggregated and non-personal information. We may share aggregated and non-personal information we collect under any of the above circumstances. We may also share it with third parties and our IAC sister companies to develop and deliver targeted advertising on our websites and on websites of third parties. We may combine non-personal information we collect with additional non-personal information collected from other sources. We also may share aggregated information with third parties, including advisors, advertisers and investors, for the purpose of conducting general business analysis. For example, we may tell our advertisers the number of visitors to our website and the most popular features or services accessed. This information does not contain any personal information and may be used to develop website content and services that we hope you and other users will find of interest and to target content and advertising.

Third-party websites

There are a number of places on our website where you may click on a link to access other websites that do not operate under this Privacy Policy. For example, if you click on a link to a retailer or an advertisement or a search result on our website, you may be taken to a website that we do not control. These third-party websites may independently solicit and collect information, including personal information, from you and, in some instances, provide us with information about your activities on those websites. We recommend that you consult the privacy statements of all third-party websites you visit by clicking on the "privacy" link typically located at the bottom of the webpage you are visiting.

How you can access your information:

If you have an online account or profile with us, you have the ability to review and update your personal information online by logging into your account. You can also review and update your personal information by contacting us. More information about how to contact us is provided below.

If you have an online account with us, you also may choose to close your account at any time by contacting us at the address below. After you close your account, you will not be able to sign in to our website or access any of your personal information. However, you can open a new account at any time. If you close your account, we may still retain certain information associated with your account for analytical purposes and recordkeeping integrity, as well as to prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, enforce our terms and conditions, take actions we deem necessary to protect the integrity of our web site or our users, or take other actions otherwise permitted by law. In addition, if certain information has already been provided to third parties as described in this Privacy Policy, retention of that information will be subject to those third parties' policies.

Your choices about collection and use of your information

  * You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but that may result in you being unable to use certain features of our website because such information may be required in order for you to register as a member; purchase products or services; participate in a contest, promotion, survey, or sweepstakes; ask a question; or initiate other transactions on our website.
  * At any time you can choose to no longer receive commercial or promotional emails or newsletters from us by unsubscribing from our email programs or contacting us at [prontocontent@pronto.com](mailto:prontocontent@pronto.com). You also will be given the opportunity, in any commercial e-mail that we send to you, to opt out of receiving such messages in the future. It may take up to 10 days for us to process an opt-out request. We may send you other types of transactional and relationship e-mail communications, such as service announcements, administrative notices, and surveys, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them. Please note that changing information in your account, or otherwise opting out of receipt of promotional email communications will only affect future activities or communications from us. If we have already provided your information to a third party (such as an event provider) before you have changed your preferences or updated your information, you may have to change you preferences directly with that third party.

How we protect your personal information:

We take appropriate security measures (including physical, electronic and procedural measures) to help safeguard your personal information from unauthorized access and disclosure. For example, only authorized employees are permitted to access personal information, and they may do so only for permitted business functions. In addition, we use encryption in the transmission of your sensitive personal information between your system and ours, and we use firewalls to help prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to your personal information.

We want you to feel confident using our website to transact business. However, no system can be completely secure. Therefore, although we take steps to secure your information, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information, searches, or other communications will always remain secure. Users should also take care with how they handle and disclose their personal information and should avoid sending personal information through insecure email. Please refer to the Federal Trade Commission's website at <http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/menus/consumer/data.shtm> for information about how to protect yourself against identity theft.

Children's privacy

Our website is a general audience site, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

Visiting our websites from outside the United States:

This Privacy Policy is intended to cover collection of information on our website from residents of the United States. If you are visiting our website from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. Please be assured that we seek to take reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy is protected. By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this privacy policy.

Changes to The Writers Network Privacy Policy:

We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our practices and services. When we post changes to this Privacy Policy, we will revise the "last updated" date at the top of this Privacy Policy. If we make any material changes in the way we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will notify you by sending an e-mail to the e-mail address you most recently provided us in your account, profile or registration (unless we do not have such an email address), and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our website. We recommend that you check our website from time to time to inform yourself of any changes in this Privacy Policy or any of our other policies.

How to contact us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our information-handling practices, or if you would like to request information about our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes, please contact us by e-mail or postal mail as follows:

Privacy Officer

The Writers Network

Pronto, LLC.

555 West 18th Street

4th Floor

New York, NY 10011

Your California Privacy Rights:

If you are a resident of California, in addition to the rights set forth above, you have the right to request information from us regarding the manner in which we share certain categories of personal information with third parties and the IAC companies for their direct marketing purposes. California law gives you the right to send us a request at a designated address to receive the following information:

  1. the categories of information we disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year
  2. the names and addresses of the third parties that received that information; and
  3. if the nature of the third party's business cannot be determined from their name, examples of the products or services marketed.

We may provide this information in a standardized format that is not specific to you. The designated email address for these requests is [prontocontent@pronto.com](mailto:mailto:prontocontent@pronto.com).

© 2012 IAC/InterActiveCorp. All rights reserved.

Cookies:

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record keeping purposes. Cookies can be either session cookies or persistent cookies. A session cookie expires when you close your browser and is used to make it easier for you to navigate our website. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.

For example, when you sign in to our website, we will record your user ID and the name on your user account in the cookie file on your computer. We also may record your password in this cookie file, if you indicated that you would like your password saved for automatic sign-in. For security purposes, we will encrypt any usernames, passwords, and other user or member account-related data that we store in such cookies. In the case of sites and services that do not use a user ID, the cookie will contain a unique identifier. We may allow our authorized service providers to serve cookies from our website to allow them to assist us in various activities, such as doing analysis and research on the effectiveness of our site, content and advertising.

You may delete or decline cookies by changing your browser settings. (Click "Help" in the toolbar of most browsers for instructions.) If you do so, some of the features and services of our website may not function properly.

We may allow third-parties, including IAC companies, advertising companies, and ad networks, to display advertisements on our site. These companies may use tracking technologies, such as cookies, to collect information about users who view or interact with their advertisements. Our website does not provide any personal information to these third parties, but they may collect information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw and/or clicked on the advertisements they deliver, and possibly associate this information with your subsequent visits to the advertised websites. They also may combine this information with personal information they collect from you. The collection and use of that information is subject to the third-party's privacy policy. This information allows them to deliver targeted advertisements and gauge their effectiveness. Some of these third-party advertising companies may be advertising networks that are members of the Network Advertising Initiative, which offers a single location to opt out of ad targeting from member companies ([www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)).

Web Beacons:

Web beacons (also known as clear GIFs, pixel tags or web bugs) are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of web users or to access cookies. Unlike cookies which are stored on the user's computer hard drive, web beacons are embedded invisibly on the web pages (or in email) and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence.

Web beacons may be used to deliver or communicate with cookies, to count users who have visited certain pages and to understand usage patterns. We also may receive an anonymous identification number if you come to our site from an online advertisement displayed on a third-party website.
